Hey everyone. What's going on everybody?
Sorry, my wife is in the room. How's everybody doing?
Good. Good, good. Yes.
Thinner crew today. Looks like we're thinner out getting to the end.
Um, man, I apologize. I was, have been pretty sick all week,
so my energy's a little bit low, but it's all good. My time is yours today.
Um, who had a fun weekend? Anyone, anybody got good stories?
Went to San Diego Zoo. That wasn't too bad. Little birthday party.
San is wild. Yeah. Yeah, I went when I was there. Super nice zoo.
Yeah, pretty cool. Got, uh, my other window.
I got the new surfer announcement for their new AI integration with Matt
Diggity, stuff that's dropping today.
Nice. What is, um, what's diggity stuff that's, that's, uh, integrated?
Yeah, so I, I, not positive to be honest. I,
it literally just started at the same time. This is gone. Um,
it's supposedly gonna write the content and, and optimize it and I,
I don't know the, uh, the details though.
Okay, nice. Yeah.
Yeah.
I like Matt. Matt's Matt.
So I've known those guys for a long time. So yeah,
Matt's a super good dude. I like him a lot. Really nice guy. Um,
yeah, I mean, honestly that, like, it's not even that much of a promise anymore,
right? I'm like, I, I a lot of tools do it, but I I I,
I've definitely been waiting for, you know,
I do think like the next big step when it comes to ss e o tooling is like,
I've said this before, but like, why are we still doing the SS e o? Like,
why are we still doing the work? You know? Um, it actually, you know,
tools like ARUS and EMR are amazing, amazing platforms,
but I just think that there's a huge opportunity
for, and I'm starting to see it from like some micro tools,
some micro SaaS companies that are starting to do like, you know,
basically what like big and surfer are doing,
which is like push button ss e o, you know,
like there should be software that's being developed that just
does the work for you. You know,
there's still so much manual effort that goes into the search work,
and it's really kind of like the two-prong part of AI and SS e o part
one being the generative search results, which, you know,
people just announced last week in terms of AI helping to find searchers,
find better results.
And then part two is like the AI actually replacing humans to do the SS e o
work, which, uh, you know,
I'm actually kind of like waiting for that to happen because SS e o is still so
much work,
Like's too many
Nuts about how much work it is,
And there'll be more things, more things to do. I,
I've been using OnPage AI a little bit too, and that one's fairly automated.
And then there's a new one by one of my buddies, Andrew Ainsley,
which is Content Sprout, and that's dumping out a bunch of good AI content.
He's just starting that too, so.
Nice. Yeah, we've been working closely with Julia McCoy, um,
and her company content at scale. Well, she's not her company. She's like,
you know, president, marketing, whatever. Um, but you know,
to be blunt,
like I haven't really released it yet because I haven't felt like it's really
at the point where it's spitting out content that's worthy
of promoting to the audience.
But I really do see it in terms of the next year,
especially for this company. Like, we're already,
we're just kind of waiting to find the right software to help us with this,
but essentially building like a one person agency,
a one or like two person agency that, you know, it's gonna be very,
very possible in the next year to do a million bucks in revenue off,
like with no help, you know,
if you're just like a machine of a person or if you have a, there's
Really just two of us, and then we've got our devs and uh, a designer.
But I mean, we're pretty much there already, but we've been, yeah,
We're, we're pretty lean too, man. I mean, we only have
five full-time people, I would say,
and just a slew of contractors that we use for, you know, like analytics,
design dev, stuff like that. But like, our core team is really five,
maybe even four people if you look at it that way. Um, and I remember, you know,
when chat g p t first came out and my first reaction,
I think like a lot of people was kinda like, holy s**t, this could be bad.
But then I was like, actually, I, I may never need to hire somebody ever again,
which is like the most amazing emo amazing thing is like a business owner.
It sounds f****d up saying it, I guess, but it's like, you know, it's,
I mean, and there's always gonna be people, you know, of. We, we,
of course we just onboarded some,
some companies that never even set up their analytics. Like,
I don't care how many tools you put out there for 'em or how many Chad GBTs,
they're not gonna know what to do or even desire to do it. So
Yeah, I agree. It's kind of like I liken a little bit to like social networks,
right? In that like,
Facebook has aged and turned into a platform for like boomers, you know,
I would say Instagram is more for like millennials. TikTok is like Gen Z,
you know what I'm saying? Like, it's kind of the same thing, right? Like people,
people don't know what they don't know. And I agree. I mean, like, dude,
this client, our biggest client, our biggest, biggest client,
like by far and away,
doesn't have anybody to do anything like either from like a knowledge point of
view when marketing or like execution point of view. And they crush it.
They do a ton. Um, so I agree. Like I think that there's,
there's gonna be opportunities still for like Web 2.0
services, right? Which is what we're doing now.
And then I'll call like web three services,
even though it's not really web three, but like AI stuff and you know, um,
things along that nature, which yeah, I think that's a, that's a fair point. Um,
okay, so anybody have any questions? Anything they wanna lead off with today?
Um, again, I apologize. I was sick this week. I,
I was supposed to prepare something on hiring sales reps. I have it, I just,
I haven't polished it. I'll get to it on the next time. Um,
but I just wanna open this up today. Just do some, some q and a,
anything sales related, anything, anything related to, if y'all just wanna chat.
My time is yours. Go ahead Michael. Looks like you got something.
Yeah. Um, so, uh, I'm curious, um, I, I've heard,
heard some recommendations about people asking to get like, uh,
business insurance,
but then you were saying like the agreements are pretty solid as far as like if
there's any kind of dispute. Um, I,
I just didn't know if you had any thoughts on that.
Like if you guys do business insurance or like that, that's worth it.
Um, I wouldn't be the person to ask for it.
Like if somebody who knows that space is telling you to do it,
then I wouldn't say no. I mean, uh, there's a lot of things that,
let me go back to the agreement part real quick.
Basically what I was saying with the agreement part was that for the most part,
if you're doing deals that are less than $5,000 a month,
maybe then even $10,000 a month, people,
it, it's just not worth it to really go the legal route.
It's better to just be like, untangle it and just go, um, because,
uh, just like not only the financial burden of bringing in a, a,
an attorney for both parties, but also the stress man,
if anybody's ever been through a lawsuit before, like it is an incredibly,
incredibly stressful thing to go through. Um,
so that's kinda what I was referring to.
Michael was more along the lines of like, the agreements are good,
they'll hold up. Um,
you should obviously have an attorney review it anyways,
just to be familiar with like your business, your practice. Um,
and if you don't have an attorney, I do suggest that you have somebody,
you don't have to put them on retainer,
but just have somebody that you can call email if something happens.
'cause it's inevitable, you know,
something inevitable will come up actually going through it now with my past
sales rep, um, disputes over commissions, but like, um, you know,
had to send his employment agreement to an attorney 'cause he's claiming all
these commissions that just, frankly, nonsense, but whatever the point is,
is that it's good to have somebody they can rely on. Um, and we were just like,
let's just send 'em some money and just move on. Um,
so the agreement will cover you, but if it's a very,
very large agreement right, or a very, very large scope,
it's best to have an attorney probably put something together that's a little
bit more, um, customized to your needs.
Noah just sent a link about business insurance. Uh, to be blunt,
I don't even know if I have business insurance. Um, that's,
That's who we use. It's a,
it's like a hundred bucks a month or something for a million bucks. Like,
it just lets me sleep better at night, to be honest. Yeah. Like, that's it.
That's fair.
Yeah. Yeah. I,
I think it, I like my sleep.
Small investment for a potentially large upside
Plus it makes me laugh when I see their name is his Cox. I don't know. Whatever
Worth the money, huh? Yeah. Um, again, I, I like,
it's tough for me to get up here and talk about things that I am not prepared to
do. So that's why it's good to have people around you that, um,
specialize in this type of thing. I would say it's a very small investment.
I know at my previous agency we did have business insurance and it was up to,
it was like up to 10 million protection. Um,
but yeah, I mean, I would say if people are telling you to do it, Michael,
then I wouldn't not do it because of me. I, again,
the agreements that I was just talking about, really for the most part,
we're talking about things that are going to protect you in the
short term almost with some of these clients when you're locking into something.
Especially too, if there's a disagreement over scope, right?
If they're expecting something or whatever,
it's always just gonna be able to point to,
and that's probably the most impactful thing, right?
Is that there's inevitably not,
but like at some point you're gonna run into a client who you have a
disagreement over scope.
And that's why we're in agreement is really impactful because before it gets to
attorney, your law firm, you just point to the exactly what they signed,
you know, um, and exactly what you promised. So our,
Our agreement, like I'll I'll say right now our agreement is super one-sided.
Like it is just,
it is all about us and it protects us and it says that we can
fire you anytime we want for anything. And you forfeit everything. And my,
my theory is, and, and this is what my attorney told me,
put whatever you want in it. And if they argue,
then we can change it for that specific case. Nobody ever says anything. Um,
and uh, another thing, like we have devs and we do a lot of design and we're,
we're in the back end of the site all the time and so let 'em get hacked or
anything that happens, the first thing they do is they try to blame my team.
So yeah, I just, you know, we, we put,
there's a plugin for WordPress we put in called Simple History that just logs
everything everybody does. And then we've got the insurance and you know,
we just c y a anywhere we can just 'cause we got our hands on everything.
Yeah, I agree. That's smart. So smart. Also too, um,
I'm not sure if the template that has that I give out here has it,
but I know my past agency we had something in there about, um,
not being liable for algorithm updates. Um, yeah,
same because that's another big one. We just haven't had an issue, honestly.
Like I, I, I just, I feel like if you get somebody penalized,
do you get somebody penalized in today's algorithm? Like you probably,
you probably deserve to get sued because you probably did something super
egregious. Like it's really, really, really hard to get somebody penalized. Um,
I, I think for the most part,
algorithm penalties are kind of a thing of the past, but it's again,
it's good to have that in there. Um, because to Noah's point, you know,
it's inevitable,
especially when you start to scale and get more and more clients.
People are unpredictable, you know, something happens with their business,
they're always looking for somebody to blame, you know? Yeah.
Makes a lot of sense. I appreciate that. Of course.
Anybody else, questions, comments? Go ahead Connor.
Yeah, I have a question. It's not really sales related, but,
and if this is something to take somewhere else,
that's fine on keyword research. Sure.
I'm in the middle of doing that for a client and
it honestly just sucks. And I dunno if it just sucks and it sucks,
or if like I'm doing something wrong or I'm like over perfecting it and thinking
that there's some like perfect solution that I'm missing.
But the keywords that I'm finding, like I just,
I don't think are like all that great.
And I'm trying to think about those bottom funnel keywords.
But most of this bottom funnel keywords are just so competitive and
so broad that it's like gonna be hard to rank a winery website
for, you know, wine tasting near LA or something like that.
Sure. Do you wanna drop me the, the file? We can, I can share my screen,
we can take a look at it for
Sure. This is the content workbook.
Are you just pulling stuff with big volumes or are you looking at like zero
click keywords
To,
so I pulled stuff from like three competitors
that I thought were probably the best and just chipped it,
chipped away at it from probably like a thousand keywords to now down to
a hundred. And then I added in my, uh,
the existing pages that could use a ReadWrite
Okay. Using
A keyword research tool to find the stuff that the competitors aren't ranking
for. 'cause competitors usually aren't, aren't the end all be all by any means.
Yeah,
That's true. Um, I'm using SEMrush, um,
but I really didn't,
I really have mostly just went off of keyword gap.
Yeah.
And then done some
Interesting because they, you know,
they probably haven't found 80% of what's out there too.
Like we use Mangos and then we use keyword gap and then
we do all the competitor analysis and just pull in everything we possibly can.
But I, something I've done over the last year or two is, you know, even stuff,
if it says it has no volume for that bottom of funnel, like we get clicks on it,
you know,
it says zero volume and I'm pulling a hundred clicks a month off of a hundred
keywords. Like that's volume to me, so.
Hmm.
Yeah. Um, so it actually,
so you said that you felt like this was too competitive, Connor?
I mean like the ones that show up are like listicles.
I'm competing against a lot of listicles for that.
Got you. 18 wineries,
best wineries. Yeah. All listicles basically. Right. Um,
but then again, also, I mean this is gonna be our opportunity here,
the maps pack. Mm-hmm. Um,
so which I would say is also probably gonna be your,
but I would just say it's gonna probably convert the best anyways. Uh,
this listicles stuff too. This is honestly like, I'm actually like,
one of the reasons why I'm excited for a generative AI is 'cause like,
I hate listicles and like, to me this is like the worst search result.
And when you're trying to plan anything like restaurants, travel,
things to do when you're traveling, like this is such a bad experience. Um,
and in the past I would've said something like,
well you can try and pitch to get included in here. Um,
which is still an option 'cause you'll get a really good link and also a good
placement from it. But like,
they're probably not gonna be paying you enough to do that. Um,
unless you see this coming up over and over and over again, which you might.
But again, I would focus on, on the local stuff here. Um,
so anything winery near me plus location I would
be optimizing here for. Um,
I just, so
One of the things that we talked about last week was just like getting,
even honing in on the offer even more,
especially since I have such a specific niche,
but I also have sold a number of clients, like, um,
this kind of thing. At least that's what I like essentially told them.
And so I'm trying to still do it and get it done for them because that's what I
said I would do. Um, even though I'm,
I'm feeling like I just don't know that reporting, giving them a whole list,
you know, of this content workbook of Oh yeah,
you can make some content talks about how many glasses are in a wine bottle.
Like that's just not that valuable. But I said I would do it,
so I'm
Okay. So you're stuck. Well, I mean, in the future I wouldn't, go ahead. No,
it looks like you had something to add too.
Yeah, sorry. I, I,
so I just popped it in my keyword tool and there's variations that are standing
out to me. Like, so what I did is I did winery near me,
but I just did it for LA County. Um, and like vineyards near me,
600 searches a month with pretty much zero competition. Uh,
local wineries near me buy wine near me. That might be more liquor store,
but dog, dog friendly wineries near me. Mm-hmm. Vineyard tours near me,
winery near me now. Um, wineries open near me,
wine merchant near me, uh, wineries with food near me. Um,
outdoor wineries. So a lot of like distinctions maybe,
maybe they allow dogs, maybe they've got outdoor stuff, maybe. Uh,
we've got black owned winery near me, so there's, people are digging in on this.
So there's a, a lot of opportunity here. Maybe winery lunch near me, um,
you know, indoor, all that stuff. And,
And the good thing too that I'm seeing here too, so like I took,
I took vineyards, I'm obviously not near LA so I had to put it in,
so it might vary a little bit,
but wine vineyard LA Winery is near LA wine tasting near la.
One thing that you see here is this San Antonio winery is ranking for all three
of these, um,
which is a really good sign that you can get all of those
keywords that no potentially just listed off to get the single G M B to rank
for. Yeah. Right. And that, and that's, and and again, Connor,
because you specialize and work with wineries,
like what we have is we have a spreadsheet of like,
it, it's basically a pay-per-click spreadsheet,
but where we'll just do a concatenate
location plus all these valuable bottom funnel keywords. So like,
instead of doing this, right, and I know that you said that you did it,
but what I would do is I would just say, look at,
we're gonna push this off to the future because we right now we're gonna focus
on getting new clients and then we'll do the content later.
I would just be building a list like using keyword research,
but also off the top of your head using, um,
people also search like all these different things down here, um,
to put together a list of these like bottom funnel keywords for wineries.
And then all you have to do is whenever you take on a new client,
you basically just flop through the location. Right. Um,
so all those things that Noah just said too. And I also think too,
what's good about what things like dog friendly, et cetera,
you put that on the website,
you build a page on the website for that to build some relevancy,
but also within these listings,
I believe that you can put like
Services, any of that stuff. Yeah.
Like dog friendly. I, you could even do like reviews from people to ask like,
Hey, I brought my dog, it's a great place to bring your dog.
You know what I'm saying? Like mm-hmm.
A bunch of different things that you can get on here. Um,
Google posts do a post about how they're dog friendly with pictures of dogs
'cause Google's great images now. So
Yep. All that. So this is actually, um, you know,
all this stuff down here, like this is cool, right? Like I,
I I wouldn't say not to do this,
it's just none of these are probably gonna really drive
any customers
For, for certain wineries. This one is like a premium,
like $150 a bottle kind of winery uhhuh.
So like the top of funnel stuff is just not gonna,
I think isn't gonna work. And when I position those to him, he's gonna be like,
well that's not really our target customer who's like trying to figure out how
to get wine stains out of a shirt. Like that's just a more, uh,
like entry level wine drinker.
Whereas what they're serving is like people who can afford to spend a hundred
dollars plus a bottle,
Right? What, what wine goes best with my Lambo. Um, um, yeah.
But I mean, I think, I think that's fine, right? I mean I, I I think
that even makes me even more of an argument to just focusing on this stuff,
you know? Yeah. Like creating the content is might drive some traffic,
might pick up some domain relevancy. So like, it's not bad to do it,
but your focus should definitely be on getting them ranked in maps pack
for as many of these keywords as possible. Yeah.
And let it, let it just kind of filter out. I mean,
if you get a thousand eyeballs on it and a hundred of 'em show up. Like,
another thing is, I've got a lot of clients that tell me who they're, you know,
this and that and I only want this. And I don't know, half of 'em don't know.
Like I, I just, I I try to drive 'em the traffic they need and you know,
if people look at it and say, Hey, that's too expensive, then so be it.
But yeah. Um, even just by virtue of their geographic location,
if it's pulling in from map pack, like those people, they're not poor.
Even just living in California,
you gotta have a little bit of money to see even exist out here. So.
Yeah. And also too, the thing with search is that like when,
especially when it comes to like these bottom funnel keywords,
like you can't really control who search is, right? I mean,
obviously with content you can be a little bit more mindful and thoughtful of
it, right? In terms of like luxury wine pairings or like high-end wine,
like stuff like that. Um, but again, like I don't, like, I,
I don't, I don't really see that helping them build more customers.
I would definitely just focus on the bottom funnel stuff,
which should trigger mass pack,
which is gonna also save you from having to navigate around these listicles.
'cause like, I guarantee you, guarantee you,
I don't even need to look at the data, the search data from if they,
not that we have it, but like if somebody's looking for winery near, like, yeah,
they might click on this, but they're coming back here, you know, like this,
this is, this is actually what they're looking for.
Q and Q and A too. I I don't know if you filled out their Q and a,
but you could put in there like, you know, what are your price ranges?
Do a question and then it's, it's okay if you do your own answer to it. Uh,
do you allow dogs dropping your keywords in there? You know,
is it family friendly? Do you have live music? Uh,
q and a really drives a lot of stuff for us.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay. Yeah.
So all these, all these things that he's talking about, Connor,
they're controllable within the backend of G B P managing the G B P.
So for this client, I, we have them on uh, four pages, uh,
four content pages. So like,
sounds like we were saying just don't even try to do top of funnel stuff.
Like just focus on making pages that are going to focus on like,
you know, near LA stuff like that. Like I would bottom funnel.
Yeah. And that's gonna be mostly controlled on Google Business profile.
I would just make sure that the website also reflects that maybe like an f a Q
page or like their booking page. Just make sure that, so like,
like the core of of your work here should be like, like I,
I wouldn't say delete all this, but like,
just have another tab that's like bottom funnel or something, right?
Mm-hmm.
You only have these and then like the ancillary terms around that too,
which is like outdoor view, sunset, you know,
dogs allowed vineyard types of wine, you know, that they have, you know,
white wine, red wine, all like all the different things, food experiences,
it has it on there. Everything that like, are kind of like, oh,
if you think of it as more like a, like a like a word map, right?
That like our surrounding kind of what the core terms are,
that's what you wanna focus on.
A lot of that is gonna be controlled through Google Business profile,
which is good,
but you just also wanna make sure that you have that on the website as well.
Right. Okay. So like,
you should have a dedicated page with like the page title that's like, like,
I don't know, best winery, like best wine. Like, like, so like you could have,
if you also look at these two,
you could probably break these down into like service pages or something.
I wouldn't maybe not call 'em service pages, but like, I don't know, features,
whatever
Offerings maybe.
Yeah. On the, that are dedicated pages on the website.
That'd be like wine tasting, wine tours, uh,
like I don't know if they have like classes or anything, you know,
stuff like that that just build out again,
like a little bit more depth and relevancy that those patients can rank for.
But like a large majority of this is gonna come from Google business profile.
Um, 'cause all of this ranking here,
there's obviously some onsite stuff that helps, but this is gonna be highly,
highly, highly coming from. And this one here crushed it.
I mean this one is ranking for all them. I would probably do a, oh there
They're good.
2,900, yeah, 2,900 uh, photos, 1800 reviews.
Um, I would do a lab, look at all these Q and a.
They have 79 questions and answers on here too, you know, um,
this would actually probably be a great place right now to go through and Yep.
Um,
We do it all the time. Yeah.
How much is the wine tasting? So pricing
And you can ask and answer both with, with your company. We just, we try to,
you know, do a name change for the person answering,
but it's Google's fine with it as far as I know.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
And then on your, on your location pages or whatever, dropping in,
driving directions from outside la from different highways,
from different geo targets that, that can help too. Yeah.
Distance from la distance from San Diego. Yeah.
Embed it, making sure you embed uh, Google Maps. It slows it down a little bit,
but I think it's worth it.
Yeah, definitely parking. Yeah, these are all great.
I would, I would snag these and add these all in.
These aren't necessarily keywords. I would say. These are more like,
I don't know, I don't know what the word would be, ancillary terms,
helpful terms, but these are all things like, you know, I I,
I have to like heavily train and work with my, my content team.
'cause they tend to get a little bit too bogged down in keywords,
like just keywords.
But these are like the exact things that I believe that Google's looking for
because Google wants to serve what people are looking for and like if you're
using this for your on-page FAQs or like on-page kind of like targeting, right?
As opposed to like just looking at keywords. So for example, um,
if like these are the only ones with volume,
these are definitely gonna have zero volume down here. Like no volume, maybe 10,
but like definitely no volume. So a lot of SCLs would be like, okay,
like these aren't valuable keywords.
I'm just gonna focus on building a page that's just about wine tasting,
you know,
in LA or close to LA and then just find as many keywords and put those as like
subheadings.
But then you have a page that doesn't really read or function that well when
instead I believe that Google's looking for this type of stuff because like you
can't come to this page and look at these questions and reviews and not say that
this is exactly what people are looking for. You know,
Go into the g p too and go into the, um,
the keywords that the G P's ranking for inside the profile.
And they give you a list of everything that you're coming up for and just make
sure some of your content matches that stuff. Um, you know,
if you see that you're, you're showing up in map pack for dog friendly winery,
but you have no dog friendly winery content on the site,
once you drop that content on there, you could double,
triple the number of impressions for that stuff. Yeah.
Okay. Okay. That's really good. Thank you guys.
Of course,
I had another question. That's cool. Yeah. Um, so, uh,
the last training session you were talking about, um,
I I think you kinda just kind of like alluded to it and it kind of got me
sparking some ideas, um, with warm outreach mm-hmm. Uh,
with your leads you get from ads. So it, it was,
I've tested like both and I,
I I run traffic to A V S L and then like they go and book an appointment and I
follow up with those people.
But I also tested like where you have like that front opt-in so that they can
see the V S L. Mm-hmm. And I got a lot of leads.
Some of them were like marketing managers and other people were just like other
SEOs and that's, that's fine. Right. But, but there was still some,
definitely some, i I would say viable leads. Um,
is that kind of what you were talking about? Like, could, could we follow up,
does that fall under like the realm of warm follow up?
Like the people that maybe put the name and email address and the phone number
in but didn't actually book an appointment or what, what
Are your thoughts on? Yeah, it's a great question Michael.
So we have tested incest. So,
so for what Michael's referring to too, for everyone,
just for bringing everyone for context is A V S L is kind of like a
new market term for like a, basically a, a prerecorded webinar,
but it's very short, very truncated, very to the point.
We've run them all the time.
You've probably definitely seen at least one of ours throughout the years. Um,
there's different schools of thought on
the contact capture for the V S L, right?
So running traffic to it to get their name and email,
then to see the video to get their name, email,
phone number to see the video or just running what we call naked,
just so they consume it. And then if it's really good,
then they'll kind of path on their own to book the call.
We've tested all of them, all of them. Um, if you have a,
a, I don't wanna call it like an aggressive sales team,
but if you have somebody who's dedicated full-time to sales,
it's worth it to get the phone number. So name, email, phone number,
because you can just give them a buzz.
And we were doing this a lot at Blueprint when we had,
we've like really descaled our sales team.
'cause I just think that in the coaching and training world,
like the whole like book a call model has just gotten really beaten to death.
And people are just like, I just,
just gimme the information and I'll decide if it's good for me.
I don't need you to be,
I don't need you to like for you to text me like 30 times a day. Um,
so I think for the blueprint, we scaled that down, but for a while,
what was working really well is we were running paid traffic to A V S L or
to like a tools, what templates, whatever we get their name, email,
phone number, they would get added to an automated email sequence,
which would then be pushing them to the ultimate goal,
which is like education plus book a call or to watch the V S L.
So that's what we use the email automation for on the V S L page too.
We'd have a button that says like, we can do this for you. Like click to book,
click to find out more,
and then it just directs you directly to account lead booking to book a call,
right? So that's like the full flow. Then what we would do is we would have, uh,
like a junior salesperson,
we called them like an appointment setter or whatever who would call and just be
like, Hey, this is Steve with a blueprint training,
saw that you opted in earlier today to check out our video.
Did you get a chance to watch it? Do you have any questions? Right?
And just kind of like build that rapport and conversation.
It's like an extra touch point.
And then ultimately we would try and get them to book a call with a closer or a
sales rep, right? It worked really well for a while. Um, but when you,
as soon as you put that phone number on there, two things happen. One,
conversions go down, uh, significantly go down. Two,
you get a lot of fake phone numbers. A lot, a lot of,
I had never put my phone phone number into those forms anymore because like I
already know, like, I don't want to get, like, to me a text me,
there's like a whole,
like people who swear by text message marketing and open rates are like 90%
blah, blah. I'm like, yeah, because everyone opens their text messages.
But it's also like really,
really annoying in my opinion to get a text message outta the blue from like,
I just don't, I, it's not for me.
So like I stopped doing it because I don't ever do things that I don't
personally do as a consumer.
And like I'm never excited to get a phone call at three in the afternoon from a
sales rep that I like didn't schedule with. You know, like I don't,
I don't even want to like show up to some sales calls that I've booked. Um,
so I stopped doing that. But it does work,
especially if you're set up to do it right?
If you have somebody who doesn't mind getting on the phone and just doing
outbound dials and if we've also got like your V S L dialed in where you're
getting those for, you know, less than 40 bucks or so,
then it can make sense to call them up.
So what we do though is we just run it with name, email, um,
and the call to action that we use too is where should we send it? Right?
So that way people will put in there the right email. 'cause if not,
if you're just like putting your email and like you'll get it right away on the
next page, then people would fake email just to unlock it,
go to the VSL and then be gone. Um, and I still am a huge,
huge believer in building an email list.
I think it's one of the more valuable and underappreciated assets,
even though it continues to decay a little bit.
But I also think we've kind of hit the floor for email list,
which is around like 20% open rate, two to 3% click rate,
right? Which means you just have to build a pretty big list.
But having that email list is a great asset because it also comes in handy for
ads to like upload those great audiences. Just, it's,
it's a really good asset to have. Um, so
we do that. Um, and then we use,
we've also kind of backed off 'cause our data has shown that people don't really
book from an email, right? So like for example, you get the email opt-in,
a lot of people will just like go straight for the jugular and be like,
book a call, book a call, book a call. Like, Hey, you opted in for this video,
book a call.
We've moved more towards a focus on consumption,
meaning let's use the email sequence to make sure that people are watching the
video. Because if you watch 10 minutes of a video that I do, then like,
you're gonna be a pretty warm sales lead or at least like interested in booking
a call. So we've really changed our, our method and approach to that. Um,
and really tapered off. And then, you know,
we just add them to a future email list and we'll make them kind of like micro
offers to like join Slack or you know, get 'em into our Facebook group,
which also works really well that we get a really high join rate to our Facebook
group off that. Um,
but really the key man is like putting together really good B S L and that is
like,
where I think marketers go wrong is they're so focused on the other parts of it.
But in reality the most important part is putting together a video asset that
like if somebody watched it, they're like, f**k, that was good. And like, yeah,
I really wanna talk to these people, you know? Um, so I think put,
and that's where also like, that's why we just tested. We,
we will just run VSLs directly as an ad.
Like no need to click just like video view campaigns and then we'll just
remarket offers off the back of that. Um,
'cause if we have like a really good engaging video,
like I did one like probably six months ago at like ss e o being dead,
but like not really being dead that went viral on YouTube that we were just
like, we just have to get people to see this video.
'cause if they see this video, like two things are gonna happen.
You're either gonna really find me annoying or you're really gonna like me and
potentially wanna work with me. And like,
I'm okay with alienating 75% of people to work with the 25% of people that I
f**k with, you know? Um, and yeah,
that video got a lot of engagement and then we would just remarket offers off
the back of that, right?
So like there's a number of different ways you can do it.
There's no right or wrong way to do it.
It's more about what your business is set up to do.
Like if you've got a really good sales team that needs leads,
throw a phone number on there and just have them, have them,
have them make dials and, and do it.
I know like Traffic and funnels does it a lot, a lot of companies do it. Um,
but to me, I think the most important, important part is that video asset,
like that video asset has to be able to like, for every 10 people that see it,
like at least three of them have to wanna book a call. If not,
that's like what you should be focused on, right? And then you have an asset.
I mean we've been running our like sprints,
productization V S L for like a year and a half now and it's generated more
revenue for us than anything by far. Like when people watch that video,
it really tackles a pain point that people are feeling, right?
Lack of profit in their business working too much, uh,
issues with staffing and hiring consistency with results. Um,
and it just ties perfectly into our, our core offer here, which is sprints. Um,
go ahead. No, it looks like you have a comment. I think
That's the one you got me with.
Yeah, it's got a lot of people with it for sure. Um,
I was wondering, um, this is kind of like a marketing question, so,
'cause 'cause I've, I've definitely tested in my V S L like drives appointments,
which is great. And so I just stuck with like showing them the V S L,
but I did see the value also of like getting like the name and email address and
all of that. But, but you know, like Facebook algorithm,
like I feel like a lot of SEOs were, you know,
even if it was like aimed at like, let's say attorneys as an example, you know,
um,
they would still put their information in I guess just to see the information.
And I,
I don't know if I'm mistaken thinking that maybe like the algorithm takes that
and then starts showing it to more SEOs.
Like it starts good and then my list becomes like more focused on just
SEOs, which is super annoying.
I didn't know if like you had any thoughts on that, like, or how
It happens. Um, I mean, who are you, who, who are you targeting?
Who's your I C P?
Yeah. Right now it's just probably B two B I'm gonna be starting, uh,
LinkedIn as well. But like my Facebook marketing, um, is just genetic broad,
broad targeting.
I would, I mean,
I would try and I would try and specialize a little bit deeper than that because
you're gonna have that issue. Um, B two B is very broad. I mean, like,
I consider myself a B two B marketer, like I don't do e-commerce anymore. Um,
but at like a very high level business offer, that's fine,
right? Because it, like, I think B two B marketing is very,
is very specific for a marketing execution point of view.
But if you're like a law firm or a contractor or
you probably don't look at yourself as a B two B company, right? And that,
and that's I think as lawyer technically as B two C, right?
A contractor is technically B two C,
but they run off of like a lead generation model, right? Which it would be,
I would consider B two B marketing personally, right?
I look at B two B marketing, it's probably maybe the wrong way to classify it,
but anyone who needs like leads who, who runs on a sales model, you know? Um,
so that could be like a software company. But again,
like when we're talking about software versus law firms, like,
it's dramatically different, right? So like what does B two B actually refer to?
We're allowing them to self-identify, which causes a lot of confusion. I mean,
even with Facebook probably, right? Like, I don't think anybody, very few,
I mean the only people that probably identify as B two B are marketers, right?
And that maybe that's the issue that you're having if you think about it. Like,
if you think about like what people's job titles are,
what they're talking about, if they're talking about B two B,
like they're probably not a home services contractor, right?
They're probably another marketer. So it's very,
very important that you think through that and your messaging is also so, so,
so important. Um, because,
you know, pretty good example is, you know, we get a lot of, I mean,
you're just gonna get marketers whenever you're talking about like a marketing
tactic, hack, whatever. I mean, s**t, I just,
I literally have an email right now inbox from a,
a company who does like lawyer marketing 'cause they had a really good offer and
I'm like, damn, I wanna see this. Maybe I'm missing something. You know,
so like, it's inevitable,
like you're gonna get people like that that just opt in because they want to see
it. Whatever, that's fine. There's nothing you can do about that. Yeah.
But again, if you're very,
very specific with who you're targeting,
like calling out law firms or contractors or SaaS companies,
Facebook is gonna react to that very favorably.
Like they're gonna find those people to, they're very, very good at
basing off what your messaging is and you're targeting finding the right subset
of people, but also within that your messaging is so important.
Like what I've found working with law firms,
is that a lar I mean like a huge majority of the market is,
is solopreneur law firms. Yeah.
Which are just not qualified to work with us.
They just don't have the cash flow to pay more than a thousand bucks a
month. It's actually a huge misconception about the law firm market.
So I I, go ahead. I've been, sorry to interrupt. Um, I,
I've been trying to like nail down, you know,
I had a lot of success with a client.
They had like 6,000 web pages and it was insane. Like, you know, they,
they had the assets, you know,
the ability to just implement what I recommended and within like 90 days,
like 200% of their web traffic. And it was like amazing, right?
And I didn't know, like, like I can't,
I'm struggling to like find like how to niche down to like, how,
how do you encapsulate, like I, I know I can't be like, Hey,
do you have a big website? You know, like, like what,
do you have any recommendations or like any industries that kind of are flushed
with, with those types of people? Or is that just kinda like hit or miss?
So like internal marketing people, like internal marketing teams,
like software is good, but actually, I mean,
software's just getting hammered right now. You know,
I don't like the layoffs are crazy. Um, that's happening.
But like, yeah,
I mean like software companies are usually ones that I would say is an industry
that you can talk directly to marketing managers or marketing teams.
Um, but I mean,
law firms do, but like only the top big law firms do, you know? Um,
so no, I would say they don't. But like, also this isn't,
this is a good conversation because I think that a lot of the times
we want to make an offer based on what we think the market is or what we think
is best. But a lot of times we have to adjust our offer based on what we see.
And that might be a good example. We're going through it right now,
I'm telling you like the amount of law firms that we get that want to work with
us, but I'm just like, oh, I can't do it for 2000 bucks a month, dude.
I'm sorry. It's just too competitive like that.
Like you can't even buy links with that. Um,
so we're working on like a lower ticket offer for those types of
people for down sells, right? Because there's nothing we can do.
We can't change the market. We just can't. Right? Uh, but at the same time,
like I'm not gonna dedicate, you know, time and resources to,
to try and work with 'em because it's just not the model that I wanna do
anymore. So when you're running ads,
it's one of those things when you're paying for them, like you're like, I I,
I don't wanna just burn these leads.
I don't wanna just ignore them because they have some money.
They just don't have what we need. So like,
adjusting your offer accordingly is another thing. And again, also,
just to finish my thought from before, which is the messaging is so important.
So like,
one of the things that we're doing now is we just started a new campaign today
hopefully went live. Uh, it's like a fix my ads offer for law firms, right?
We're actually giving away like a hundred dollars Amazon gift card, gift card,
gift card.
We're testing that out as like a guarantee that within 15 minutes we'll save
them like, you know, 30%. Uh, and if we can't, then we'll give you,
we'll send you an Amazon gift card for a hundred bucks.
So obviously we're gonna heavily qualify those people ahead of time.
Like I don't foresee us ever sending out a, uh,
a gift card because the people that we actually do the analysis for,
it's kind of like a mini proposal or analysis that we've talked about here.
They're gonna be qualified and we'll be able to save the money.
But the reason why we moved to this offer was because we were getting so many of
these solopreneur law firms in and the messaging that we can tie in is if you
are spending X, then you should be getting Y, right?
So if you're spending $10,000 a month on Google ads,
you should be getting at least 10 new clients a month, something like that,
right? That allows us to qualify with the messaging super nuanced,
super advanced marketing that like you kind of gotta like figure that out within
the market that you're working in.
And that's another reason why specializing is so important because like we never
would've been able to launch that or test this or come to that if we were doing
like general B two B, right? Which we were doing for a while.
So I think from a general website agency point of view,
B two B marketing is fine and then like you specialize in certain industries,
but when it comes to advertising or just marketing in general,
it's just too saturated out there to not have a very specific specialization
that includes LinkedIn. 'cause like the algorithms just,
there's so much content, like how do they know who to serve it to, you know?
And it's also not specific enough for people to stop, right? So for example,
again, if you, like, let's say you work,
you wanna work with like contractors or law firms or SaaS companies, right?
They're all B two B. From our point of view,
if you're creating like amazing content on LinkedIn about like lead generation
and B two B companies and like talking to B two B companies,
they're probably all gonna scroll by 'cause that's not what they'd identify
with.
Versus if you're talking specifically to SaaS or you're talking specifically to
law firms, right?
Which also allows you to get so much more nuanced with your communication and
messaging.
Like Brendan's a great person to look at because just going through that
process,
he's learned so much about SaaS that he's now able to throw back into his
communication. Talking about cac, talking about L T V, talking about layoffs,
talking about the market, right?
Talking about how to make it through this and still keep your marketing afloat,
right?
It just wouldn't land if he was talking about something more general and
specific like marketing in general. Like, hey,
everyone knows like the market's s**t right now,
but like here's how like you could do it, but it's just,
it's gonna be a lot slower and you've gotta get a lot less traction, you know?
Yeah. It's the same thing. Even more so with ads. 'cause you're paying for that,
that, that, that newsfeed space, you know what I mean? Yeah,
that makes a lot of
Sense. That's gold. I appreciate
It, man. Of course.
I got a, a random one that's kind of sales related. Um,
we do a lot of c r o and I'm running a bunch of split tests,
but I'm just getting, and maybe you can help with this, maybe not.
I'm getting hammered by spam and bots filling out all our forms,
which are killing all my split tests. Um, we're using recapture,
but it's just not filtering 'em out. We tried honeypots,
it's not filtering them out. Do you guys run split tests?
Do you have any capcha that you use that actually works? How, how do you,
how do you get around that?
We don't. Yeah, yeah, we don't
Say that. Yeah,
I mean we've,
we've had like issues with Blueprint for a while with like spammer,
but like for the most part we don't have a huge issue with it.
I guess we don't run forms, we just run it through Calendly. Maybe that's why.
Um, because like we don't, we just,
all of our bookings are just directly through Calendly,
which means like if you're gonna spam us,
it's like manual spam and we'll deal with that sometimes.
Like we get some a******s out there that like don't like seeing advertisements
on their feed,
so they wanna take time outta their busy schedule to like spam our forms,
which is like mind blowing to me. Um, but yeah,
I mean maybe that's why we just don't have contact forms and that's just because
like I just see it as an extra step.
I understand why a lot of companies will like the company that this big company
that we're working with,
they use HubSpot and like pushing from Calendly into
HubSpot was kind of pain in the ass. We're like, let's just keep the form up,
have 'em go through that,
get it into HubSpot in the c r m 'cause it's such a huge po they pay so much for
it that like have to f**k sucks. I hate it. It's the worst. Yeah. Um, so like,
but now the stack that we recommend and like when we're working ground up with
companies is like, first of all, hopefully we are on WordPress because yeah,
the companies that we're not working with like a million page websites here,
you know, we're talking about like a hundred to 500 page websites,
just like WordPress is cool and then just migrate to Calendly. Um,
'cause we've now got like the stack and the people and we've done it so many
times in terms of ourselves and clients like integrating with reporting,
firing conversions, Calendly ISS amazing man. I really, I really,
really like Calendly. I just,
I'm setting mine up. I just stole half your forms together
Basis. Yeah, it's, it's, it's really,
really good because it's like getting a form sum.
It just takes care of like you get a form submission, right?
'cause we used to run this, if you go back to the old version of the blueprint,
you know, I used to run it as a form beforehand because like,
well I just kind of like what we talked about with Michael, right? It's like,
well I want to get their contact information that way I can follow up with them.
But it's like, dude, if they're not willing to like fill out a couple questions,
like do you really wanna be chasing them down? You know, like it's just not,
it's just not worth it. Now again Michael,
that's different if you're running paid traffic. And again, like I said,
if you have a sales rep who can go through emails and do a little manual
qualification to be like, okay,
actually like this guy didn't book but I went to his website and he's really,
really qualified. So maybe I'll send him a one-on-one Loom video.
And that's probably like,
the only thing that I miss too about like doing the warm outbound is that if you
have somebody, like if it's you and you got a million other things going on,
it's probably like good use of your time.
I would just focus on getting a better V S L that's gonna do that for you. Um,
but if you have a sales rep who's like looking for,
for deal flow and opportunities, that's a good opportunity to do that.
To be like, go through the email list. If they have a website attached to it,
go to their website.
And if you feel like they're a really good fit for what we do,
then like email 'em, call 'em, send 'em a loom, connect with 'em on social,
build that conversation that way. But like, the contact form, it's like, yo,
you're contacting us to work with us for services and you can't fill out three
questions. I'm like, no, like, you're just not that interested. You know? Yeah,
That makes sense. That makes sense. Alright, cool.
Uh, I have another question. So, uh, sorry for monopolizing the call.
Um, so I, uh, I've,
I've kind of like come across two types of prospects. Well, okay. I mean,
not so much this, this first person,
so one guy got like mo most of the time when I'm trying to sell like the,
the strategy sprints at the beginning. And then I, I don't have it on like,
any type of proposal or slide deck where I just say, Hey,
here's how much the strategy verse is and the content or, or sprint,
I call it verse. Um, so, uh, and, and,
and most people are cool with it. I'm like, yeah, so like,
we're going to deliver the results for the strategy burst and you know,
we're gonna have some technical ss e o fixes as an example.
It's gonna cost anywhere from like a thousand to 1500 bucks.
And like most people were cool with that. But I've had a few people that, um,
kind of like, it rubbed them the wrong way. They were,
they were kind of upset that like, I didn't like put that and like,
pitch them like in the actual documents. Like, you know, hey,
like this is also gonna be included in the expected price. I mean, like,
I kind of thought it was weird, you know, 'cause like most people aren't really,
they don't really have an issue with that. Like, if I just like simply say like,
yeah, like, we just don't know what it's gonna be. It could be a thousand,
could be 1500, but I didn't know if like there's any like standardization,
like to that. Like if, what, what do you think? Like,
should we just stick to one way and just go that way? Or what do you think?
So, standardization or versus, sorry,
like cut my Oh, that's okay.
Yeah. Yeah. Basically like, should I just maybe try to incorporate like,
you know, putting something there like, um, you know, hey, it's gonna be may,
maybe sometimes it'll be 750 bucks, whatever, right? To, to make the changes.
But like,
we'll just like upcharge a little bit to protect our margins and make sure
that're not doing any work for free. And just say like, yeah,
so once we finish the strategy burst,
we're gonna have technical ss e o recommendations and it's gonna be a thousand
bucks or 1500 bucks and just like, keep that price. Or, or what do you think?
So, sorry man, I'm, I'm like blanking on this one for a second.
So basically you're asking me about changing pricing based on what you think
that they're willing to pay or based on their feedback. Yeah,
so like having elastic pricing based on
Yeah. Yeah. Pricing based on, well, I just, yeah. 'cause I had a few people,
not a lot. So it, you know, most people are cool with it when I'm like, yeah,
strategy versus this, we're gonna find technic c recommendations.
It could be anywhere from thousand to 1500 bucks, like,
depending on what we find, you know, and we can do that for you if you'd like.
Um, but then some people were upset. They were like, oh,
well you didn't put it on the actual proposal.
Oh, okay. So
I like how to handle that. Like,
Uh, well, I mean, ideally you just tell them during the sales process, right?
Um, if not, then I'll just be like, well, okay, then, like,
he's gonna have to fix them. I mean, you, you know, like, I, I,
I get it. Um, you know, and I would just say, yeah,
I mean that's, I mean, or if they're like really mad,
you just eat the 500 bucks, whatever it costs and just do it for them.
If it's not a lot, you know, um,
if just save face and like build a little s**t in the bank, if you will.
But yeah, that's something that you definitely have to like,
cover it during the sales process and the proposals that like,
the outcome of this sprint will be X, y, z, um,
you have a developer? No. Okay, well if you wants to fix this,
which we can, we just have to charge, you know, an extra fee, um,
basically what you just said, you know,
depending on the scope of the corrections, it could be two hours,
which will cost you X or it could be 10 hours, which will cost you y but like,
we're not gonna do that unless you approve it, obviously. Um,
I just wanna let you know ahead of time that we can handle it,
but it's not included in this, in the cost. Okay.
You kind of have to charge for it, man,
because when it comes to those technical issues, like it can just be a wormhole,
an unraveling thing. Like, I just had,
my wife's website got hacked, um,
and I thought it was gonna be an easy fix, two hours worth of work,
but it took the dev, my dev two days and it cost like almost a thousand bucks.
Um, you know, so, you know, you never know what these things,
you just have to, you have to charge for 'em. 'cause it can,
it can really be a kick in the nuts.
Okay, cool. That's awesome. Thanks.
I don't dunno if that helped me. I don't dunno if that's what you're asking.
No, no, it, it, it did. I just, because again,
like 90% of the people are like totally cool with it. But then, like this guy,
he was sold, like, I can read people now, like he was ready to go.
And then as soon as I gotta that part,
he just like immediately just changed personalities and got upset
and then told me later, like, you know,
And that was, that was during the sales process or after,
Yeah, during the sales process. He was like, cool, like, let's do this.
And I should've just taken his card right then and there, you know,
but then like, I then explained, you know, then he asked about that, like,
you know, what, what happens like with the findings, you know,
do you guys do that? And I was like, well, no, no. I mean,
depending on what we find, you know, and this is why I don't quote it up front,
because like, it could be 500 bucks could be Oh yeah.
And he didn't like that. He was
No, he didn't like that. He, he, I guess maybe he's been burned in the past.
I don't know. It was weird.
Yeah. Okay. I mean, I, I, I understand both sides,
but if you like a rational human being should understand that. Like,
you're gonna find things and that you just don't know what they are, you know?
Um, sounds just kind of like a bad apple on on. Yeah.
Did you end close enough
From, uh, common common sense then? No. No. I didn't close them,
No. Because of that.
Yeah, that's what he said. He like sent me an email the next day and he,
it listed off like that and like, two other reasons, like why he,
but it was just, I don't know. He, he seemed very, again, like a bad apple.
Like, he just seemed weird, you know? Um, so that's unfortunate.
Um, Connor asks,
could you give your script for what you say about technical s e o actions being
a separate cost? I don't really have a script for it, Connor.
It's more of just a, after I run them through the sprint, you know,
I let them know that there's gonna be a series of actions that we'll put into a
matrix for them.
Some content actions that we'll take care of during the content sprint. Um,
and then potentially some technical actions as well that, um,
would likely require the, the help of a developer right now,
like I think it's important to break it down for them a little bit, maybe too,
if it's like, okay,
if it's something that we can go into the website and like change page titles,
sure, that's one thing. But if we're talking about, you know, I don't know,
uh,
a directive in your robot's T X T file, that's like hindering performance.
Like I have to get a developer to, to change that. Um,
and it's gonna be an extra cost. 'cause like, so
You're not gonna charge for changing like 500 page titles
or embedded descriptions?
I mean, no, because we're, we would do that during the content sprint portion,
right? Like, you see what I'm saying is that like,
we're only gonna change a page title per se. Like,
we'll send them the recommendations if they want. Like,
that's a conversation to have, I guess. But, um, you know, for the most part,
if we're changing page titles, it's gonna be like, oh, I'm not just gonna like,
go through the entire website and rewrite page titles and change 'em when an ss
e o tool does that for me. Absolutely. Um, but like to,
it's just like too much work. And it's also like, it,
it just requires such a concerted effort to like, do the queue research,
do some research per page title that like, we'll only do it,
we're actually updating a page with content homepage, like maybe, you know,
a couple of them takes,
What if they have zero page tiles, zero meta descriptions, basically,
Then I would assume it's a very small website.
And like that would be something that you could, like,
if it's a winery website with like 20 pages, like yeah, you can just do that.
Just knock it out. Um, yeah,
What my question was, like in the sales process,
when you're going through and saying, Hey, um, strategy sprint,
foundation sprint, it's, you know, x you know, $3,500.
That does not include, are you saying like,
that's not gonna include any tech technical access that might come up from it?
That would be like an additional hourly cost? Yeah,
Just, just the implementation, right? Like, it, it's like not,
right? Like what we're talking about here is very common. You know, the,
it is just, I guess we're going out of our way to communicate it, right?
But like mo, like nobody does a technical audit and makes the actual changes.
It, it's just like, first of all, there's so much risk involved with it. Like,
you don't wanna just be f*****g with the technical aspect of somebody's website.
Like, we're not developers, we're marketers, you know,
and that's an important thing to tell them is that like,
we do have people that are developers, but like,
you're putting us on an ss e o contract.
Like this is not a web development contract. So just like,
there's gonna be actions about content. Like we're not writers, you know,
we have writers to do the writing if needed. Mm-hmm. But like, we're,
we're doing an ss e o audit. We're, we're doing ss e o work. Um,
it's just a different skillset. Like, just like design,
like we're not gonna redesign your pages. You know, we can if you want us to,
but that's not what we're talking about here, you know?
Okay.
Um, Nestor asked, well, we'll be going over pricing breakdowns. Um,
absolutely went, we went over one-on one of the calls, nester,
I think it was the third call, but I'm happy to go through more. Um,
when we went through like the proposal stuff and the scoping,
we went through pricing breakdowns.
But I'm happy to go through more on the next call if you'd like.
Just gimme some, I mean, if you wanna like,
maybe drop a website that you want me to, to price out,
I'm happy to do that live for you with you guys to go through that process.
Pricing's very important. So happy to spend some time on it.
Anybody else?
Yeah. Um, I was wondering, I know we talked a little bit about it last time,
but it looks like a lot of the outreach I'm gonna be doing is, is gonna be cold.
And I just wanted to get your idea on, or multiple ideas on.
Sorry. Oh, you're good. Um,
I just wanna get like multiple ideas on what you guys have seen maybe worked for
you in the past before you leaned on warm outbound.
And if there's anything that I should, um,
Consider. Yeah. So here's my recommendations for cold.
They're gonna be completely opposite sides of the spectrum,
but unfortunately this is just like such an extreme thing.
It's like only one of the other works. Um,
so option one is just like a mass brand prey option where you're sending
as many emails as possible, and that's probably gonna be the most effective way.
Um, the reasons why don't like that.
I mean, obvious reasons. It's not good for the brand. It's annoying.
Uh,
it'll probably beat you down mentally because people are gonna tell you to f off
and maybe rightfully so. I mean, I've done it for people too. Like, uh,
like I just, it's like a pet peeve for me.
Like when I log into LinkedIn and I have like 30 messages and it's all just
people having conversations with themselves. It's like one of the, like,
I didn't answer off the first three. Like, you don't need to send me 35. Like,
I'm, I'm not gonna answer. Um,
so I just think that it's also like
the window for it to work. Like by the time you figure it out,
it's gonna take months. It takes, it's like cold outbound.
It's not something you just like find a list, drop an email to, and like,
I got new clients. Like, it's a very, very long process in terms of testing,
messaging, testing platforms. Do I do this on LinkedIn?
Do I do this on Facebook? Do I do this on, uh, email?
Like how do I get those people? How do I find them? How do I vet them all that?
Um, it's a big, big, big process.
I just think in the next probably six months to a year,
like there's gonna be AI software that does outbound completely automated,
and it's gonna get to the point very quickly where people are never, ever,
ever going to respond to cold messaging anymore because it's just gonna be so
commoditized and it's gonna be so overwhelming.
And there's gonna be so much of it that these,
like Gmail's probably gonna have to just like ban those emails coming out.
And that's the other thing too, is that like,
when you take this massive spray and pray approach,
the amount of domains that you have to churn through, like it's,
it's like alarming. Uh, like there's a whole process that there's,
there's companies and contractors dedicated to it.
They call it like warming domains. Because what happens is when you do email,
if you're doing outbound email, cold email,
this is probably why a lot of people use LinkedIn instead,
but you basically burn out your domain because these email
servers are like, dude, you sent a,
you're sending a thousand messages a day and like nobody's responding.
And a lot of 'em now are going to spam.
They basically just shut down your domain and you cannot send outbound emails in
that domain anymore.
Gmail actually has like a limit on how many you can send per day.
So there's like this whole concept and philosophy of warming up domains,
meaning like buying separate domains.
'cause you can't do it on your company's domain extension. If you do,
you can literally crash your whole email server and you'll never be able to send
emails from your company email. Again, it's like a whole thing. Um,
so that's a spray and pray approach, um,
where you're just sending as many as possible and you're literally just hoping
that, you know, you send a thousand emails,
you get three back that are interested,
you end up moving forward with one of them, you know,
and then you just do that day after day after day after day.
And I know there's companies that do that successfully, um, very successfully.
Um, but it's exhausting and it's a lot of work.
And I also, like I said,
I just think that that's sales process is very elongated then because you have
to do so much convincing for people. Um, so that's option one,
the spray and prey. The other option,
which I am more of a fan of because it's better for the brand,
the success rate is higher. It's still very low, but the success rate is higher.
Um, is more of what's called like a b M,
which stands for account-based marketing. Um,
account-based marketing is like the,
a concept that was developed or a strategy that was developed for
companies who like can't do marketing because the audience is so smaller,
so niche, and it's a combination of sales and marketing together.
That's kind of like my take on it. And LinkedIn is a great platform for it.
LinkedIn ads are also very effective for it. It's basically saying,
I'm gonna build a list. It might not be huge,
but I'm gonna build a list of people that,
or companies that I really wanna work with because I know for a fact that they
check all the boxes in terms of they are the right size,
they're in the right industry, they've got the right people on the other end.
They, um, have enough momentum in their ss e o or marketing already, where like,
it's not starting from zero. So whatever that criteria is,
you build that list and you build it very detailed.
You get as much information on those people as possible, social media profiles,
email, et cetera. Just send like a mini c r m or spreadsheet.
Then you find out what the best way to connect with those people is or interact
with those people, add 'em on social media, you know,
don't overwhelm 'em with messages, but, you know, follow them for a little bit.
See what they're sharing. And like, so like,
you're basically collecting data on these people and then you,
you're very strategic with how you reach out to them, right?
Whether that's an introduction with something of value to them,
whether that's sending them like a gift or something in the mail doing like hard
mail, like old school hard mail to their actual location, um,
is another great one. There's actually a book, it's book, it's called Giftology.
I would suggest that you read it. I read that one. Yeah. It's a good book. Um,
that's, this is more of like the Giftology style outbound sales,
like outbound sales works. I'm not saying that it doesn't work.
I just think that if you're gonna do it,
it has to be on the more of account based, account based marketing. And like,
that's also where it ties into the warm stuff too, where it's like, okay,
if we're doing that, we're not doing it to everyone.
We're doing it to a small list of people.
What's the best way to break in with these people? Right? Um,
and that's why the warm style is so much better because you're getting them to
raise their hand of something,
of interest that then opens those lines of communication that you can have with
them, like we were talking about with Michael. Right. So, I mean,
what is your company telling you? Are they, what are in terms of, um,
direction that they want you to take when it comes to outbound? Have they?
Yeah, so we're just, this is all brand new, like I said. Okay. Uh, we,
we've grown organically for two years, so they have done zero, um,
like outreach. Um, but we've got all three referrals.
So ultimately they hired me. They, I'm gonna be doing, I mean,
we got LinkedIn to Cognium, uh, which is database. Um, and I can,
I can get pretty granular with it, um, which is pretty cool. Um,
so I've been building lists that way. Um, haven't done any outreach yet,
but I'm, like I said, I was, I think I'm gonna train myself just doing looms,
just so I can just get good at breaking down websites. Mm-hmm. Even if it works,
doesn't work, we can test it out. Um, but the marketing, um, my marketing,
uh, advisor,
he's basically gonna help me with measuring these things and like split testing
and basically putting these in a spreadsheets and then like, yeah,
obviously doing all the different things that you do there. Um,
so there's not really, like, I'm also gonna be doing cold calling as well, um,
and just try to, I'm just gonna test all the different,
all the different waters and just see kind of what works.
But I definitely wanted to get your opinion on Yeah.
On this realm and stuff before I, you know,
waste time on things that don't need to be wasted time on.
Yeah. I mean, waste time is very, I mean, you're, it's just like, it,
part of the process of getting that to work is like, wait, not wasting time,
but like, you're going to Yeah. Have to like, figure it out on the fly.
I, again, I like, this is just me and I,
I know a lot of people don't agree with me, but like,
and, and the logic that they use is like, well, it works.
Like it's worked, right? And like,
cold calling is one of those things where it's like, dude, I don't know.
I get so many phone calls in the middle of the day that like, I don't even,
like, I barely pick up the phone from people that I know, you know, like to,
to like get in touch with somebody who is like,
busy doing me meaningful work that like, basically, in other words,
like somebody that you'd actually wanna talk to, it's very slim. And like,
just ask yourself like, do you think that, like, you calling them randomly,
do you think they're gonna be excited about it in any way, shape, or form?
You know? Um,
I think it's a very good character building experience.
Like if this is kind of like your first time in sales,
like what that will do for you mentally in terms of sharpening the blade and
making you just kind of like mentally tougher and it, it'll be good for you.
Right? Um, but I don't know, I just like, I, I just,
I just like, I, I don't think that like justifying by saying like,
if you do a hundred dials a day and you, and you generate one lead,
that's a success. You know? Mm-hmm. I just think that, to me,
there's just better ways to do it.
And that's like focusing on focusing on identifying people instead of spraying
and praying. Like focusing on identifying people.
A list of 500 companies and people that you're like,
I don't care how long it takes, but like,
I can actually tremendously impact their business because
like that type of energy too. Like if you're just calling off of a list,
like you don't know anything about them, anything about their business, like,
you don't really have that level of confidence, but like,
it's a whole different energy if you're like, yo, Ryan, like, and this is where,
this is where outbound works.
'cause like I've hired plenty of people out of my email before my video editors
that I'm paying like almost three grand,
four grand a month for both my companies. They emailed me outta the blue.
But like, what they did that was amazing was they went through my videos, right?
And they were like, yo, like I found this video on your channel.
I've been subscribed for a while. I really like your stuff.
Like I've learned a lot about s e o from you and building agencies and stuff
like that. And like,
I'm a video editor and I wanna show you what I can do. So like,
I took two of your thumbnails and I improved them for you. If you upload these,
you'll see the clickthrough rate difference, I promise. Also,
I took one of your videos and did 30 seconds of editing to see how much more
engaging I can make it for you. Because like,
if you get more people engaged on your videos, they're gonna stick longer.
And when they stick longer, you're gonna rank higher.
You're gonna get more views, right? So like,
taking that amount of time and energy to do something, I was like, okay,
these are, this is dope, this is good. Right? How that translates to ss e o,
like you can just feel that's just much different, right? Like,
that's somebody that I wanna work with. You know?
It's the same thing that we've talked about here in terms of like the
consultative sale approach.
Like when you take the time to when you invest your time and energy into
somebody's business, like they're,
they're much more likely to give it back to you in terms of,
in terms of capital, right? So that's just my opinion.
I think that your time instead of like beating yourself down mentally and like
doing a hundred dollars a day and just like taking this like Wolf of Wall Street
approach, like I just think that people are different now and like people,
it's just highly, highly intrusive. So I don't like text message working either.
'cause it's like, it's just you're way too, go ahead. No,
Um, I was just gonna say kind of on the same vein,
something that that's unpopular that,
that I do that I don't know why I get a lot of pushback when I talk about it.
We just, we rank our own website for ss e o terms and we,
we use geo-targeted city pages and I get a lot of leads inbound because
they figure if I can rank and I can beat other s e o companies,
then I can rank for them. And, you know, I mean we, we get five,
10 leads a week just off a ranking and, and you know,
like we own pretty much all the terms in like Denver,
but out here in California,
I just pick smaller cities and smaller areas and it's pretty easy to get.
I I think everybody automatically thinks the barrier to entry is pretty large
with ranking your own stuff. But, you know, if, if you're an ss e o agency,
you should at least be able to rank in the city that you're in and,
and it works real well. So just my 2 cents on that.
Yeah, that's awesome. We're, uh,
we're currently rebuilding out the website right now so that we can reflect all
of the work that we do for other companies. So essentially it's like,
like I said, they've been very like minimal, done very little just because it's,
everything's been flowing. But yeah, we're,
we're moving into that phase right now where it's all expansion.
So I think that's definitely something we're gonna do as well is like,
is make our site, um, s e o uh, compliant.
Yeah. It, it's funny how many agencies don't rank their own stuff.
Sure. Yeah. Um,
Well thank you guys. I appreciate the, uh, the breakdown. Um, yeah,
Anytime.
Yeah, it's all helpful.
Word. Um, anybody else?
No. Alright, cool. Alright, well, uh, another productive session.
I think we have one more. We got another one too if you guys want not an issue.
Um, Nestor we'll have some pricing on the next one for you. Um,
if you have any websites that you wanna look at price out together,
you can just drop 'em in the Slack channel beforehand. And, um,
So in regards to that, so what I meant I met was, um,
what I met was pricing the, uh, or services,
so our s e o uh, sprints.
And I think you have, I think you did include a, a,
a Google doc of your pricing breakdown.
Yeah. Um, it's the pricing campaign matrix,
I believe. So I believe that's it. I wanted to see if we could like,
break that down a little bit. I know we spoke about it earlier,
I'm just a little bit confused on the, uh,
the sprints.
Okay. All right. We'll go over that on the, the next one for sure. Um,
we could spend a good amount of time breaking that down for you.
That's not a problem.
Awesome. Awesome.
I, I did actually have a question. Is, is a little bit of time sensitive,
otherwise I'd wait a little bit if that's cool.
No, go ahead. Yeah,
So, um, I'm actually, uh, this guy, I've been in the process of dealing, uh,
closing this like $4,000 a month for 12 month like contract. And, um,
I'm so close, like he,
he looked at the agreement and he is now asking me to send a W nine. Um,
is that like a form do you think I have to send or like a W nine tax
identification for the business? I, I just don't wanna sound like an idiot.
It's, that's why it's time sensitive. No, you're
Not. I mean, you can literally just Google W nine form, download it,
fill it out. It's literally just, it's so they,
it's from their point of view when they do their taxes at the end of the year
that you're a contractor that they paid. Um,
so the government knows where that money went. So he is
Not asking for like an identification number.
He just wants me to fill out a W nine basically and send it back to him. He's
Asking sign, sign. Yep. Okay, cool. You can just keep that templated sign. Yeah,
just keep it on your desktop. 'cause a lot of, I mean,
especially come tax season and everyone's gonna ask you for that.
Okay. And if, if you have a e I n use that.
Otherwise it's probably just your social if, if you're filing that way.
Okay. Awesome. Thank you guys. I, I really appreciate
It. Of course.
Um, one thing that I have that is that I'm,
I'd love some thoughts on,
I'm getting to the point where I am starting to get enough clients
regularly and get enough, uh,
revenue where I'm starting to consider leaving my full-time job now.
And I would love just some thoughts,
advice what that looked like for y'all when y'all went through that of some
check boxes, some things that you, um, did to make sure that you do that in,
you know, uh, a wise way.
And obviously it's different for everybody on your situations, but Yeah.
Anybody else wanna take that one?
I, I just jumped, I don't know. I've never really worked for anybody else,
so I just do whatever you just gotta put in the time.
I guess I, I don't really know what to say, but just do it and,
and take on all the jobs and as you kind of cruise along,
you can start to pick and choose, you know, sooner or later.
But at the beginning we did everything and we did it too cheap and, uh,
you know, gotta pay your bills at the end of the month and,
and we kind of refined it out later and, and started being picky. But I mean,
I I just say, just jump, it's probably not very helpful.
Um, for me,
I had a certain lifestyle that I was trying to keep up,
so for me it was just a matter of making sure that it was just kind of a
one-to-one transfer it terms of being able to
not necessarily make more, but just keep my bills paid mm-hmm.
For the most part, you know? Um, so once I hit that,
it took me about a year and a half to hit that. And then once I did,
I was f*****g gone.
When you were saying, so like, to hit your, your bills,
like you're consistently making, let's say whatever it is, you know,
five grand a month, 10 grand a month, and, and take home and profit. Um,
was that pre-tax or did you just like
the, the net profit?
Yeah, so I was w I was W two at that time, right? So I was making,
I don't know, for easy purposes, call it 10,000,
call it a hundred grand. So like 8,000 a month.
I was probably making like 6,000 take home after taxes. Um,
so, and off of that,
I think my bills at that time I was probably like $4,000 that I needed to like,
make sure everything was covered. So, I mean,
obviously you wanna make sure that you are not just being like, okay,
well I'm making $4,000,
so I'm just gonna put that to that because like we talked about last time, like,
you don't wanna live off the business, you wanna live off of the profit also,
taxes come into that. Um, but at the same time, like to Noah's point,
at some point you're gonna have to jump and bet on yourself, right?
Um, and something special happens when you do that because
when all of your time and energy is focused on one thing. Yeah.
And this happens with me with consulting clients, man. Like I,
I continuously do this.
I'll take on a consulting client that pays me a ton of money and I'm like,
I get stuck in the same trap that everyone does, which is chasing the carrot,
right? But then, and I'm like, oh, it's only gonna take 10, 10 hours a month,
but it's like y 10 hours documented a month. But then there's the meetings,
there's the emails,
there's the in between that I have to shift from going from this call to
then jumping over to doing that. Like, it's the same thing with a job, right?
Where uh, you know, once you remove that,
you take a, might take a step back, but this is life.
You always take a step back.
You're gonna have to always have to take a step back to take two forward.
You know,
How long were you making that, you know,
once you've hit that point where you're making pretty much like your take home
pay, you know, after taxes and all that stuff,
after all your expenses are taken out of the business,
like once you're taken from the business matches your like salary.
How long were you trying to do that?
Or as soon as you hit it that first month and you saw a trajectory,
you saw a road, did you just jump in? Or were you like, Hey, let me,
let me make sure I can do this for a couple months before I jump
Completely up to whatever your pain tolerance is. You know, uh,
that's a question that you have to answer for yourself. You know,
everyone has different levels of Yeah. Doing that.
And now after, like, I, I was never like an entrepreneurial person, you know,
I was always like taught to get a job, go to school, blah, blah, blah.
But like now, like, you couldn't pay me enough to ever go back to that. Like,
I would rather get out of a f*****g soup can
Ever and work for somebody. Fear, fear's a hell of a motivator too, man. Yeah.
Like being,
being scared that you're not gonna hit your bills is gonna make you work more
like, I hate to say it, but leverage, you know, like I,
I remember at one point I,
I was going to yard sales and buying stuff and putting on eBay to supplement.
Like, you just do whatever you gotta do, you know? And
Yeah, yeah. We're, we're in a good, we're in a good spot.
'cause my wife has her own business and like she's doing really well and there's
opportunity for me to like, help her and grow that too. Um,
we just have gotten too comfortable. Our, our golden handcuffs are definitely,
they're definitely, uh, real. And so it's like to,
to try to replace my salary job is like a pretty, you know, it's,
it's a good amount and, but like, I think it's the,
it ultimately is gonna come down to like the,
the pain tolerance and risk tolerance really.
Yeah. So,
But yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Appreciate it. Once,
Once you do it, you won't go back though, I'll tell you that.
No, I know. Yeah. It's
Enough to go back, man.
Never, never.
Hey Ryan, I
Got Yeah, go ahead. Go ahead Nestor.
So what's your percentage split bet with your profits?
Like, how much do you keep within the business? Like for example,
I'm a solopreneur. Um,
how much would you recommend at this stage that you should allocate to retaining
profits in the business and then taking home, you know,
like putting the rest in your pocket?
So I personally leave,
well, okay, so to answer that, it's more of like, what do you need to,
if you own a hundred percent of the business,
it doesn't matter if it's in the business or in your personal bank account,
right? So in my opinion, you should just leave it in the business. Um,
so I pretty much leave all my profit outside of what I take
as a salary, if you will, um,
from my companies. I leave profit in the business because I mean,
you never know what's gonna happen, right? I mean,
tomorrow Google could shut down and like all of a sudden we lose all of our
clients and I need that cash in the business to figure it out.
I can always transfer it back in, but then there's like,
it's just easier to leave it in, right? So then at the end of the year,
I'm able to take a nice fat bonus, which is great. So, um,
I think for you,
you figure out what is it that you want to or need to live off of or
what you want to live and that, like, everyone has a diff again,
a different threshold and opinion for it.
Like I know people that like take everything outta their business because they
wanna spend it and that's fine, that's their money.
They can do whatever they earned it. They can do whatever they want with it.
I personally like to, just the way that I am,
like I'm not, I'm, I'm a very risk averse person actually.
And I prefer to like live within my means,
but also, I mean, like I know I have that money if I want to take it.
'cause I own almost a hundred percent of both of all my businesses, you know,
so the cash is mine and the way my taxes are set up too,
it doesn't matter where it is, right?
But I just think it's better to keep it in the business because as soon as it
hits my bank account, I'm liable for taxes on it. Um,
and if I leave it in the business,
there's things that I can do in terms of like spending it on ads or making a new
hire where like I can invest that money back into the business.
So it's up to you. I mean, at, at the end of the day,
money's just has a number on a screen, you know, like, um, so I,
the way I have my bank account set up, I use Chase for everything.
So I have like six bank accounts between business and personal, right?
And it's all in one screen.
So like the way I look at it is that it's all in my accounts, right?
But it just belongs to different facets of, of,
of my income and wealth, right? So it's up to you. Like,
I think first thing you need to do is figure out how much you need, like,
as a bare minimum to live off.
And I think this is a valuable exercise for everyone. 'cause like dude,
all hell could break loose tomorrow. Like Covid that came out of nowhere, right?
And it f****d a lot of people.
And like to know what you need as a baseline minimum just to just to,
to to live is a really important number because that also gives you that,
it gives you your floor, right? Uh,
and it gives you like if something does happen in your business.
But the good thing about our business models too is that like you can always go
out and earn, it's just a different way of earning. You can do consulting,
you can go get a job, it doesn't, there's always things you can do, right?
But knowing what that number is, is a really important threshold.
And then from there it just becomes what do you want to spend
to live the lifestyle that you want? You know?
Yeah.
Thing I would add into that is just always make sure you're taking the money out
for taxes. Don't, don't forget that and co cover your nut. Like whatever.
You gotta pay your bills and then once you're making enough,
get a C P A because there's stuff that you don't know that that will bite you in
the butt. Uh, believe me, trust me on that. Um,
and then set yourself up so you're actually taking a paycheck. Uh,
'cause for tax purposes that's better too. So just, you know,
don't get caught at the end of the year and all of a sudden you owe 20, 30, 40
grand in taxes because you took a little too much money and didn't save
anything. So. 'cause they'll get their money. Believe me, one way or the other.
They will, they will get their money.
Yeah, I know.
Alright y'all, I gotta run. Um, but uh, hit me on Slack,
drop anything you wanna chat about next time?
Nester will do pricing stuff for sure. Uh,
anything else that you guys wanna talk about? Set us up in Slack.
I'll see you next time. Alright
Guys. Thank you. Bye.